pathfinder.org 2011-12-14

# Pathfinder International: Privacy Policy

**At Pathfinder International, we value the privacy of our donors and online supporters.** We have instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled in a safe and responsible manner. ****

**For any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy,** **please contact us at**[ **communications@pathfind.org**](mailto:communications@pathfind.org) **or call 617-924-7200** **.**

## **The Short Version:**

  * This policy covers the operations of Pathfinder International, with Headquarter offices at 9 Galen St., Watertown, MA 02472, USA.
  * We do not collect any personally identifiable information about you online unless you voluntarily submit such information to us, by, for example, filling out a registration form or making a donation. 
  * We do not share email addresses.
  * We do not retain the email address of anyone to whom you send an eCard or Tell-a-Friend link.
  * **We do not store your credit card information after processing a donation.**
  * Donor names and mailing addresses may be exchanged with other groups working on similar issues. You may request that your name and address not be exchanged with other groups, however, we ask that our donors allow us to use their names in this way to ensure us a reliable, low-cost source of new supporters. Learn more about why this is important here [link]. To request that your name not be used in our exchange program, please [email](mailto:communications@pathfinder.org "Contact us") or call 617-972-1234.

**    COMMUNICATION PREFERENCES:**

  * You may [update your information online](http://www.pathfind.org/site/ConsInterestsUser) at any time to personalize your online communication preferences including opting out of all online communications.
  * If you have other preferences or have questions about our communications practices please [contact us](mailto:communications@pathfinder.org "Contact us") and we will respond to your questions.  If you prefer to call, please call 617-972-1234.

**    COOKIES:**

  * When you register on our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a cookie or similar file in order to deliver content to you that is specific to your interests, to process a donation or to prevent you from being required to reenter all your registration data at each connection. 
  * The cookies shall only be used to obtain non-personal information in order to improve your online experience. No other information is stored in these cookies. 

* * *

## **The Long Version:**

This policy covers the operations of Pathfinder International, with headquarter offices at 9 Galen St., Watertown, MA 02472, USA. 

By visiting our website, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy"). Pathfinder reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting such change at this URL. 

**INFORMATION COLLECTED**

**Personal information you choose to provide:**

We do not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you voluntarily submit such information to us, by, for example, filling out a survey or making a donation. The types of information that may be requested include your name, address, email address, and telephone number to respond to a specific request for further information. 

You may request a record of your information by calling (617) 924-7200 during normal business hours, Monday-Friday, 9:00am-5:00pm EST or by e-mail at [communications@pathfind.org](mailto:communications@pathfind.org).

**Additional Personal Information you may provide:**

Occasionally, Pathfinder may contact registered website visitors who have provided their personally identifiable information through the website in order to conduct surveys seeking feedback about their experience on this website. These surveys are used for quality assurance purposes to improve our level of customer service. The data collected may be shared with third parties _on an aggregated basis_.

Through the use of some forms (donation, survey, registration, etc) you may be asked to voluntarily submit comments or other opinions on various topics. 

We do not retain the address of anyone to whom you send an eCard or Tell-a-Friend link. We would only get their information if they voluntarily provide their personal information to us.

**Non-personally identifiable information:**

Pathfinder collects non-personally identifiable information about you through your IP address, computer settings or most-recently visited URL.  

**USE OF INFORMATION**

Pathfinder respects your privacy and has instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled in a safe and responsible manner. **By submitting personal information to us you agree that we may use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.** We will update this privacy policy as we deem necessary. You should be sure to re-read this policy in its entirety form time to time

**Personal Information you choose to provide:**

**We do not store your credit card information after processing a donation.** Pathfinder assumes no responsibility for the data collection and use practices of third parties that process online credit card donation transactions.

Personal information you choose to provide will be used for the purpose it was intended. We may also use this information to deliver to you information about Pathfinder International, related activities or as otherwise disclosed to you at the point of collection, as well as for trend analysis, pattern detection, and website administration. Donor names and mailing addresses may be exchanged with other groups working on similar issues. You may request that your name and address not be exchanged with other groups, however, we ask that our donors allow us to use their names in this way to ensure us a reliable source of new donors. [Learn more about why this is important here](http://www.pathfind.org/site/PageServer?pagename=PrivacyPolicy_donorexchange "Learn more about why this important here"). To request that your name not be used in our exchange program, please [email](mailto:communications@pathfinder.org "Contact us") or call 617-972-1234.

We will only disclose personally identifiable information to other third parties when (i) the person submitting the information authorizes us to do so; (ii) sharing the information is a necessary operation of the website (i.e. to process credit card information); and/or (iii) we are required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Pathfinder or the website; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Pathfinder, the website or the visitors to the website, and/or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of visitors to the website or the public.

Non-personal demographic and profile data may be used to tailor your experience at our website, showing you content we think you might be interested in. 

**Comments/Opinions**

Comments voluntarily submitted by users on forms, surveys, petitions, and donation forms may be used anonymously in Pathfinder International online and/or print communications. You may request that the comment not be used by contacting [communications@pathfind.org](mailto:communications@pathfind.org). Pathfinder will obtain specific permission to use comments which will be attributed to your name. By visiting this website you agree that no information you submit to the website shall contain libelous or otherwise unlawful, abusive or obscene material. You are solely responsible for the content of any information you provide to Pathfinder.

**USE OF COOKIES**

  * When you register on our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a cookie or similar file in order to deliver to you content that is specific to your interests, and to prevent you from being required to reenter all your registration data at each connection. 
  * The cookies shall only be used to obtain non-personal information in order to improve your online experience. **No other information is stored in these cookies.**  

**SECURITY**

  * Our website has industry standard high encryption security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 
  * **We do not store your credit card information after processing a donation.**
  * Pathfinder makes every effort to protect your online order information by using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. SSL encrypts your order information to avoid the decoding of that information by anyone other than Pathfinder. 

**OTHER WEBSITES; LINKS**

This Privacy Policy only applies to Pathfinder International maintained websites including, but not limited to, [www.pathfind.org](http://www.pathfind.org/) and [www.girl2woman.org](http://www.girl2woman.org/). This website contains links to other websites that are not under Pathfinder's control. Pathfinder is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. Pathfinder is not responsible for the privacy policy of any website linked to or from this website.

**COMMUNICATION PREFERENCES**

You may [update your account online](http://www.pathfind.org/site/ConsInterestsUser) to personalize your online communication preferences including opting out of all online communications. If you have other preferences or have questions about our communications practices please [contact us](mailto:communications@pathfinder.org "Contact us") and we will respond to your questions.  If you prefer to call, please call 617-972-1234.

**DISCLAIMER**

This website and all of the materials on or referenced by the website are provided on an "as is" basis. In no event shall Pathfinder be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, punitive, or consequential damages of any kind whatsoever with respect to the use of this website. You agree that you are using this website solely at your own risk.
